

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







MCSA, CSM Business Analyst III & Scrum Master seeking roles in IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Analysis, Use Cases, User Stories, Gap Analysis, C#, SQL Server, Python, JIRA, TFS, Microsoft Test Manager, Quality Centre, Balsamiq, Snagit



Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: United Kingdom (UK), Singapore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Business Analyst III & Scrum Master,IT Project Management,Requirement Gathering,Business Analysis,Use Cases,User Stories,BRD,FRD,SRS,Gap Analysis,C#,SQL Server,Python,JIRA,TFS,Mcrosoft Test Manager,Quality

Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MTech [Data Science and

Notice Period: 2 Months

Engineering]

Centre,Balsamiq,Snagit,Informatica,SSIS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Sr. Business Analyst & Scrum Master with around (9) years' experience in implementing end to end technology solutions Experience in business requirement elicitation and converting user requirements into functional requirements. Hand-on experience in preparing the BRD (Business Requirement Document), FRD and SRS, User Stories creating Design Documentation and Test Plans.

Experience in working across multiple geographic locations and variety of clients.

Strong technical aptitude and experience with the software tools and techniques used in testing.

Strong communication, collaboration & team building skills with proficiency in grasping new technical and functional concepts quickly and utilize the same in a productive manner.

Experience in conducting joint application development JAD sessions with end user, expert team, Business intelligence team, IT SMEs and QA team for project meetings, walk through and all stakeholders.

Work Experience

• Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd as Business Analyst & Scrum Master Mar 2011 to Aug 2020

Worked as Business Analyst for Bank Of America in various domains which include Payments, Global Markets and Financial Crimes

Roles and Responsibilities:

Worked as Business Analyst and Scrum Master in payments domain for multiple releases of SEPA, SEB, VAT1.0, VAT 2.0 and FTR.

Draft and maintain business requirements and align them with functional and technical requirements. Gathering Requirements from the Clients and preparing Requirement Understanding Document (RUD).

Interaction with Business Partners to understand the project objectives, use cases and requirements Monitoring project progress by tracking activity, resolving problems; publishing progress reports; recommending actions

April 2015-June 2016 Business Analyst * Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd Client: PODS

Worked as Business Analyst for transportation client Portable On Demand Storage and supported

Roles and Responsibilities:

Gathering Requirements from the Clients and preparing Requirement Understanding Document (RUD). Interaction with Business Partners to understand the project objectives, use cases and requirements Monitoring project progress by tracking activity, resolving problems; publishing progress reports; recommending actions

Designing the UI mock-up screens in order to incorporate with BRD.

Preparing Functional Specification Documents and Business Requirement document comprehensively documenting the expected system behavior in various business scenarios and preparing & maintaining Traceability Matrix. Coordinating with Operations and IT support team present at onshore and Explaining business requirement to

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. tecnnical resources

Training the development and QA members on Domain specific functionality

August 2014-March 2015 SQL DBA* Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd Client: Bank of America

Worked as DBA for an application which receives data from various data providers/sources and get loaded into CSDR data repository through a complex ETL process. CSDR basically is a single source of data repository for all BOA compliance and surveillance requirements. Multiple downstream systems consume the data of CSDR for various business requirements like Trade Surveillance, Reporting tasks etc.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Monitoring the server for High availability of the servers

Involved in mentoring team members and writing documentation

Performed weekly tasks including backup and restore by using SQL Server 2005 tools like SQL Server Management Studio, SQL Server Profiler, SQL Server Agent

Exported data from other data sources like flat files to SQL server using Import/Export

Involved in creation of SQL Logins, Roles and Authentication Modes as a part of Security Policies for various categories of users.

Updating the Passwords of the service accounts used throughout the application in the scheduled periods Performing monthly maintenance activities like patching and reboots for servers in NLB, HLB and in cluster Created packages using different sources, transformations and destinations like Excel Source, Flat file Source, OLEDB source and OLEDB destination

Worked with control flow items like Execute SQL Task, Sequence Container and Data flow task.

March 2013-August 2014
Database Analyst * Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd
Client: Avanade

Worked as Database Analyst for Avanade Contact center Solutions (ACCS), which is a set of ready-to-use contact center solutions or accelerators that are largely missing from Mcrosoft Dynamics CRM. It is an integrated solution that helps enterprise organizations across industries improve customer satisfaction, reduce agent turnover and increase agent engagement while meeting business objectives to increase productivity and control costs.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Involved in deployment of Mcrosoft Dynamic CRM and SharePoint solutions
Involved in exporting case data from Mcrosoft Dynamic CRM database to client specific SQL database
Also involved in data validation and migration to SQL

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Computer Science and Engineering) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2008

PG: M.Tech (Data Science and Engineering) from Birla Institute of Technology and Science (BITS), Pilani in 2020

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Certified Scrum Master

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
MS OFFICE		
MS Visio		
SQL		
JIRA, TFS		
HP QUALITY Center		
Microsoft Test Manager		
Windows 10, Fedora, Unix		
Informatica		
Microsoft SSIS		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.